# Logan Buchanan

I make games & other things

skills

phone: 604 786 5766

code
C# unity
javascript illustrator
html/css photoshop
lua excel
php jira

email: iamloganbuchanan@gmail.com

web: www.LoganBuchanan.com

### profile

I'm a game designer with a background in Interactive Media and User Experience Design. I have 3 years of professional game design experience in mobile & PC games, and I'm looking to take on ambitious projects with teams I feel connected to. I take a holistic approach to game design and I voraciously seek out new design methods and practices. I hope to collaborate with all disciplines of development to make truly great games I'm proud of.

## work experience

#### **System Designer:** Beamdog Inc.

unannounced project | Unreal 4 | gameplay & meta systems

- Lead the design of in-game character and level progression systems including stat scaling, perks, loot, and randomized 'shrines'
- Designed all core meta-game progression systems including talent trees, currencies, and selectable 'loadouts'
- Collaborated with combat and gameplay designers and engineers to integrate systems with all aspects of the project

#### **RPG Designer:** Kabam Inc.

Marvel Realm of Champions | Unity3D | gear & quest design

- Designed 100+ unique gameplay passives spread across 20+ gear sets that provided unique gameplay adjustments to all champions in-game.
- Lead the design of a story event mode called World Quests
- Worked closely with a team of gameplay, content, and rpg designers to help concept and tune champion loadouts and abilities

#### Game Designer: Nexus Media

Paragon Kingdom: Arena | Unity3D | hero design | balancing

 Balanced a mobile MOBA with 14 heroes through internal testing and statistical analysis

- Designed and helped implement a PvP map for 4v4 mobile play
- Designed several characters from concept to implementation and balancing

July 2021 - present

August 2019 - July 2021

May 2018 - July 2019

# Logan Buchanan

I make games & other things

email: iamloganbuchanan@gmail.com

phone: 604 786 5766

web: www.LoganBuchanan.com

January 2018 - April 2018

## academic projects

Game Design/Development: The Furrow

team of 3 | game designer & developer | Unity3D | 4 Months

 Designed and implemented a tactical turn based rogue-like from the ground up

- Built and tested several key gameplay ideas through paper and digital prototypes
- Took the lead in systems and ability design to create a tense and engaging experience for the player

## education

Simon Fraser University: Interactive Arts & Technology

bachelor of science | Grad. April 2019 | 3.7 GPA

2015, 2017, 2018 Open Scholarship for Academic Achievement

September 2014 - April 2019

### interests

I mainly split my time between biking, music, and running tabletop roleplaying games. I use biking as a tool to get some alone time, while my music and RPG habits allow me to have regular time with my friends, as well as a strong creative outlet. I'm always looking for new ways to share these interests with others, and I'll probably ramble for far too long about any one of them, so I think I'll just stop here.